Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine.
我是Catherine。
What's wrong Catherine?
Catherine，你怎么了？
I'm just a little down today.
我今天只是有点低落。
You're having a, you're in the mood, you're not in the mood today?
你是有点……你心情不好，今天没心情吗？
Is that what's going on?
是这样吗？
I am not in the mood to record today.
我今天没心情录节目。
Actually no, I am in the mood.
其实不是，我有心情。
So we're talking about moods, feelings, emotions.
所以我们今天要聊的是心情、感受和情绪。
This is today's podcast and we're going to be learning a lot of the names for different
这就是今天的播客内容，我们将学习很多关于不同
kinds of feelings.
感受的名称。
That's right, so you're going to learn how to describe what mood you're in.
没错，所以你会学到如何描述你现在的情绪。
Maybe you're in a good mood, bad mood, etc.
也许你心情好、心情不好等等。
So let's just jump into the dialogue and see what's going on.
那我们就直接进入对话，看看发生了什么。
Are you okay?
你还好吗？
You seem a bit anxious.
你看起来有点焦虑。
Yeah, I'm okay.
嗯，我没事。
I've been having a lot of mood swings lately.
我最近情绪波动很大。
I think it has to do with the pills my doctor prescribed that are causing chaos on my hormones.
我觉得这跟我医生开的药有关，它们让我的荷尔蒙乱套了。
So you mean you feel ecstatic one minute and then blue the next?
所以你的意思是，你一会儿感觉狂喜，一会儿又感到忧郁？
Yeah, it's weird.
是啊，很奇怪。
For example, just this morning I was feeling detached and lonely, even though there was
比如，就在今天早上，我感觉疏离又孤独，尽管
really no reason to feel that way.
真的没有理由那样感觉。
Well maybe your mood will swing positively and you will feel confident, brave and hopeful.
嗯，也许你的情绪会积极转变，你会感到自信、勇敢和充满希望。
I hope you're right.
希望你说得对。
Okay, lots of feelings.
好的，很多种感受。
So many feelings in fact that we're going to talk about the names of them in today's
实际上有这么多感受，我们将在今天的
Language Takeaway.
“语言要点”环节讨论它们的名称。
语言要点。
So on Language Takeaway, let's take a look at this adjective.
那么在语言要点环节，我们来看看这个形容词。
You are feeling or you seem a little bit anxious.
你感觉或你看起来有点焦虑。
Anxious.
焦虑的。
He is anxious.
他很焦虑。
I feel anxious.
我感到焦虑。
That's right.
没错。
Now this word means that you're feeling nervous or uneasy about something.
这个词的意思是，你对某事感到紧张或不安。
Normally when you feel anxious about something like a test, all you can think about is the
通常当你对某事（比如考试）感到焦虑时，你满脑子想的都是
test.
考试。
Oh, will I fail?
哦，我会不及格吗？
What's going to happen?
会发生什么？
Did I study enough?
我学得够吗？
You're worried.
你很担心。
So this is an anxious feeling.
所以这就是焦虑的感觉。
That's right.
没错。
So if you're anxious, you're worried about something or you're nervous about something.
所以如果你焦虑，你就是担心某事或对某事紧张。
It could be about your job, interview, a test, etc.
可能是关于你的工作、面试、考试等等。
All right, so moving on now.
好了，现在我们继续。
We're feeling anxious, but then we also feel a different type of excitement.
我们感到焦虑，但随后我们也感受到一种不同的兴奋。
We are ecstatic.
我们感到狂喜。
All right.
好的。
So well, anxious is a bad feeling.
那么，焦虑是一种不好的感觉。
Ecstatic is a really good feeling.
狂喜是一种非常好的感觉。
Okay.
好的。
Okay, so I'm happy.
好的，所以我开心。
I'm really happy.
我非常开心。
I'm ecstatic.
我狂喜。
That's a really, really, really happy feeling.
那是一种非常非常非常开心的感觉。
Okay, so if you're ecstatic, it means you're very, very happy.
好的，所以如果你狂喜，意思是你非常非常开心。
So it's not a negative thing.
所以这不是负面的事情。
No.
不是。
So when I get a hundred percent on my test, I'm ecstatic.
所以当我考试得了一百分时，我狂喜。
I'm really happy.
我非常开心。
Okay.
好的。
Now basically the complete opposite of being ecstatic would be to feel or be blue.
现在，基本上与狂喜完全相反的是感到或变得忧郁。
Yeah.
是的。
It might seem a bit strange because blue is a color, as you know, B-L-U-E.
这可能看起来有点奇怪，因为蓝色是一种颜色，你知道，B-L-U-E。
But when you're feeling blue, it means that you're feeling sad or down or upset.
但当你感到忧郁时，意思是你感到悲伤、低落或沮丧。
You're depressed.
你抑郁了。
Yeah.
是的。
So maybe this is why you also have music, the blues, right?
所以也许这就是为什么你也有音乐，布鲁斯，对吧？
The blues.
布鲁斯。
He's got the blues.
他得了忧郁症。
That means he's sad about something, usually a woman.
那意味着他因为某事而悲伤，通常是因为一个女人。
Aha, okay.
啊哈，好的。
So ecstatic, very, very happy.
所以狂喜，非常非常开心。
Feeling blue, very, very sad.
感到忧郁，非常非常悲伤。
And well, another example of feelings, also a negative one is if you feel detached.
嗯，另一个感受的例子，也是负面的，就是如果你感到疏离。
Detached.
疏离的。
All right.
好的。
So we know the word attach.
所以我们知道 attach 这个词。
That means to put two things together.
它的意思是将两样东西放在一起。
Well, detached means to take two things apart.
而 detached 的意思是把两样东西分开。
Okay.
好的。
So what do you feel apart from?
那么你感觉与什么疏离呢？
Other people.
其他人。
Aha, okay.
啊哈，好的。
So for example, if I'm feeling detached, maybe it means that I don't feel like the people
所以举个例子，如果我感到 detached，可能意味着我觉得身边的人
around me understand me.
不理解我。
I don't want to talk to other people.
我不想和别人说话。
I'm just not feeling very social.
我只是不太想社交。
So for example, can you feel detached in your relationship?
那么，比如，你在感情关系中会感到 detached 吗？
You can, and that's actually a really bad feeling because you should be happy in a relationship.
会的，这其实是一种很糟糕的感觉，因为在一段关系中你应该感到快乐。
But when you're detached, it means that you don't really feel close to your boyfriend
但当你感到 detached 时，意味着你并不真正觉得和你的男朋友、
or girlfriend or husband or wife.
女朋友、丈夫或妻子很亲近。
Okay.
好的。
And we feel detached and lonely.
我们会感到 detached 和 lonely。
So if you feel lonely, that means that you feel?
所以如果你感到 lonely，那意味着你感觉？
Similar to detached, lonely means that you don't feel like you can talk to anyone.
和 detached 类似，lonely 意味着你觉得无法和任何人交谈。
You feel alone.
你感到孤独。
So I'm very lonely right now.
所以我现在非常 lonely。
I have no one to talk to, no friends, you know, no one makes me feel good.
我没人可以说话，没有朋友，你知道，没人让我感觉好。
Okay.
好的。
So that means that you feel alone.
所以那意味着你感到孤独。
All right.
好的。
A lot of adjectives there, many different ways to describe the way that you feel.
这里有很多形容词，很多不同的方式来描述你的感受。
So let's take a listen to the dialogue again.
那么让我们再听一遍对话。
Are you okay?
你还好吗？
You seem a bit anxious.
你看起来有点焦虑。
Yeah, I'm okay.
嗯，我没事。
I've been having a lot of mood swings lately.
我最近情绪波动很大。
I think it has to do with the pills my doctor prescribed that are causing chaos on my hormones.
我觉得这和我医生开的药有关，它们让我的荷尔蒙乱成一团。
So you mean you feel ecstatic one minute and then blue the next?
所以你的意思是，你一会儿感到狂喜，一会儿又感到忧郁？
Yeah, it's weird.
是啊，很奇怪。
For example, just this morning I was feeling detached and lonely, even though there was
比如，就在今天早上，我感到 detached 和 lonely，尽管
really no reason to feel that way.
真的没有理由那样感觉。
Well, maybe your mood will swing positively and you will feel confident, brave, and hopeful.
嗯，也许你的情绪会积极波动，你会感到自信、勇敢和充满希望。
I hope you're right.
我希望你是对的。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now let's take a look at Fluency Builder.
现在让我们看看 Fluency Builder。
Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder。
So on Fluency Builder today, the first phrase is mood swings.
今天的 Fluency Builder 中，第一个短语是 mood swings。
I've been having a lot of mood swings lately.
我最近情绪波动很大。
That's right.
没错。
So this basically means that your mood is changing constantly, all the time.
所以这基本上意味着你的情绪在不断地变化，一直变。
That's right.
没错。
So mood is the way that you feel and to swing means to go back and forth.
所以 mood 是你的感受方式，而 swing 意味着来回摆动。
So I'm happy, I'm sad, I'm angry, I'm lazy.
所以我开心、我难过、我生气、我懒散。
So these are mood swings and it means that you're not normal, you're not flat, you're
这些就是 mood swings，意味着你不正常，你不平稳，你
going up and down and feeling many different things.
上上下下，感受到很多不同的东西。
Okay.
好的。
So to be clear, also your mood is the way that you feel at a certain time or a certain
所以明确一下，你的 mood 也是你在某个时间或某一天
day.
的感受方式。
That's right.
没错。
So you're in a good mood today.
所以你今天心情很好。
Did you get good news?
你收到好消息了吗？
That's right.
没错。
So that means that you look like you are happy or it seems that your personality is positive
所以那意味着你看起来很开心，或者你的性格今天
today.
很积极。
That's right.
没错。
Or you could say, I'm in a bad mood.
或者你可以说，我心情不好。
Don't talk to me.
别跟我说话。
So maybe you're angry.
所以也许你生气了。
Yeah.
嗯。
All right.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
Now to basically explain why we're having these mood swings, we say that, well, maybe
现在，为了基本解释为什么我们有这些 mood swings，我们说，嗯，也许
it has to do with the pills the doctor prescribed that are causing chaos on my hormones.
这和医生开的药有关，它们让我的荷尔蒙乱成一团。
All right.
好的。
Chaos is a thing.
Chaos 是一个东西。
It's a noun.
它是一个名词。
And chaos means that there's no order.
而 chaos 意味着没有秩序。
Everything is crazy.
一切都乱糟糟的。
It's out of control.
它失控了。
And so basically what this person is saying is that the pills that he's taking, it can
所以基本上这个人说的是，他吃的药，可能会
feel out of control.
让人感觉失控。
Right.
对。
Exactly.
没错。
So they are causing chaos.
所以它们造成了 chaos。
To cause chaos, to cause nothing in control and on your hormones.
造成混乱，让一切失控，还影响你的荷尔蒙。
So, but what does hormones have to do with your mood?
那么，荷尔蒙和你的情绪有什么关系呢？
All right.
好的。
Hormones are chemicals that your body actually produces.
荷尔蒙是你身体产生的化学物质。
Women have different hormones from men, but they affect the way that we feel.
女性和男性的荷尔蒙不同，但它们会影响我们的感受。
So oftentimes you could say that I'm in a bad mood because of my hormones.
所以很多时候，你可以说因为荷尔蒙，我心情不好。
Pregnant women are very famous for having mood swings, happy, sad, angry, because they
孕妇以情绪波动闻名，开心、悲伤、愤怒，因为她们
have more hormones in their bodies that they're not used to.
体内有更多不习惯的荷尔蒙。
And so they cannot control the way that they feel.
所以她们无法控制自己的感受。
That's right.
没错。
So an example is if a man has too much of one hormone, like testosterone is a hormone,
举个例子，如果一个男人某种荷尔蒙过多，比如睾酮是一种荷尔蒙，
then this person will usually be very aggressive.
那么这个人通常会非常具有攻击性。
Right?
对吧？
That's right.
没错。
And the female counterpart to testosterone is estrogen.
而女性对应的荷尔蒙是雌激素。
So if you have too much estrogen, maybe you'll be a little bit too sensitive.
所以如果你雌激素过多，可能会变得有点过于敏感。
Or emotional.
或者情绪化。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So that's what we talk about chaos and hormones.
这就是我们说的混乱和荷尔蒙。
Now, when we talked about mood swings, we take it as a noun, right?
现在，当我们谈到情绪波动时，我们把它当作名词，对吧？
You have mood swings.
你有情绪波动。
But then at the end of the dialogue, we say, well, maybe your mood will swing positively.
但在对话结尾，我们说，也许你的情绪会正向摆动。
So now we're talking, it's separate.
所以现在我们分开来说。
It's not a noun.
它不是名词。
We're taking swing as a verb.
我们把“摆动”当作动词。
To swing.
摆动。
That means, think about a pendulum, you know, a clock, it goes left and then swings right.
意思是，想象一个钟摆，你知道，一个时钟，它向左摆，然后向右摆。
So we could talk about a mood like this.
所以我们可以这样描述情绪。
So maybe your bad mood will swing the other way.
所以也许你的坏情绪会向另一边摆动。
Maybe it will become a good mood.
也许它会变成好情绪。
And so to swing here is the verb.
所以这里的“摆动”是动词。
You can maybe try and encourage your mood to swing.
你可以试着鼓励你的情绪摆动。
Okay.
好的。
So to be clear, mood swings are a noun.
所以明确一下，情绪波动是名词。
But then in this last part, we put the verb to swing to kind of explain where mood swings
但在最后一部分，我们用了动词“摆动”来解释情绪波动
comes from, right?
的来源，对吧？
So the noun mood swings.
所以名词是情绪波动。
Now you understand that it's kind of like a pendulum and it's swinging back and forth
现在你明白了，它有点像钟摆，来回摆动，
and you're changing constantly.
你不断变化。
Exactly.
正是如此。
All right.
好的。
Let's listen to the dialogue one last time.
让我们最后听一遍对话。
Are you okay?
你还好吗？
You seem a bit anxious.
你看起来有点焦虑。
Yeah, I'm okay.
嗯，我没事。
I've been having a lot of mood swings lately.
我最近情绪波动很大。
I think it has to do with the pills my doctor prescribed that are causing chaos on my hormones.
我觉得这和我医生开的药有关，它们让我的荷尔蒙混乱。
So you mean you feel ecstatic one minute and then blue the next?
所以你的意思是，你一会儿欣喜若狂，一会儿又情绪低落？
Yeah, it's weird.
是啊，很奇怪。
For example, just this morning I was feeling detached and lonely.
比如，就在今天早上，我感到疏离和孤独。
Even though there was really no reason to feel that way.
尽管真的没有理由那样感觉。
Well maybe your mood will swing positively and you will feel confident, brave and hopeful.
嗯，也许你的情绪会正向摆动，你会感到自信、勇敢和充满希望。
I hope you're right.
希望你是对的。
All right.
好的。
So talking about moods, now there are certain, well maybe like conditions where your mood
所以说到情绪，有些情况，也许你的情绪
is negatively affecting your life.
在负面影响你的生活。
Like for example, a person that suffers from anxiety.
比如，一个患有焦虑症的人。
That's right.
没错。
They have anxiety disorders and this means that they're always worried about something.
他们有焦虑症，这意味着他们总是担心某件事。
Right.
对。
So they're always anxious.
所以他们总是焦虑。
Always anxious.
总是焦虑。
So people who are anxious often tap their fingers or their pencils or their foot, talk
所以焦虑的人经常敲手指、铅笔或脚，说话
quickly.
很快。
So anxiety, it's not fun to feel anxious and you can only imagine.
所以焦虑，感到焦虑并不好玩，你可以想象。
So a lot of times these people who have anxiety problems, they will see their psychiatrist
所以很多时候，这些有焦虑问题的人会去看精神科医生，
and they will try and get some medicine, some pills to help regulate their emotions, to
尝试拿一些药，一些药片来帮助调节情绪，
help them feel in control.
帮助他们感觉在掌控之中。
Okay.
好的。
So that I think is the most interesting thing for me is because your mood is actually very
所以对我来说，最有趣的是，你的情绪实际上非常
much dependent on what's going on chemically in your body.
依赖于你体内化学物质的变化。
So as you said, you could actually balance out maybe if you're feeling too anxious with
所以正如你所说，如果你感到太焦虑，你可以通过药物来平衡，
drugs, you can actually make you feel less anxious because of the chemicals.
实际上可以让你因为化学物质而感觉不那么焦虑。
Exactly.
正是如此。
And it's also important to remember that it's not just drugs that you take.
而且记住，不仅仅是药物。
Sometimes people like to exercise and that helps them feel relaxed and calm because when
有时人们喜欢锻炼，这能帮助他们感到放松和平静，因为当你
you exercise actually, your body produces certain chemicals that help you feel happy.
锻炼时，你的身体会产生某些化学物质，让你感到快乐。
Or when you eat, sometimes when you haven't eaten, you notice that you're very, very cranky.
或者当你吃东西时，有时你没吃东西，你会注意到自己非常非常暴躁。
Oh God, why are you doing this?
天哪，你为什么要这样？
Why are you being like this?
你为什么这样？
And you eat and all of a sudden, oh, your body chemistry starts to change and so you
你吃东西，然后突然之间，哦，你身体的化学物质开始变化，所以你
feel better.
感觉好多了。
I heard that some people that suffer from anxiety disorders will be also compulsive
我听说有些患有焦虑症的人也会成为强迫性
eaters because they're nervous.
进食者，因为他们紧张。
So you know this, that some people eat when they're nervous.
所以你知道，有些人紧张时会吃东西。
This is one of the side effects possibly, right?
这可能是副作用之一，对吧？
It is.
是的。
I've heard this too, that a lot of people who are nervous or who are anxious, they overeat.
我也听说过，很多紧张或焦虑的人会暴饮暴食。
That means they eat too much.
这意味着他们吃得太多。
Even when they're not hungry.
即使他们不饿。
And this actually has a very large effect on your body because obviously, like I said,
这实际上对你的身体有很大影响，因为显然，就像我说的，
your body chemistry affects your mood.
你身体的化学物质会影响你的情绪。
So if you eat too much, your body maybe reacts negatively and you're even less happy.
所以如果你吃太多，你的身体可能会反应消极，你甚至更不开心。
It happens to me sometimes in the movie theater, like a really good scene or I'm nervous or
我有时在电影院会这样，比如一个特别好的场景，或者我紧张，或者
there's an action sequence and I'm just eating that popcorn up and I'm already really, really
有动作戏，我就一直吃爆米花，我已经非常非常
thirsty but I just can't stop.
渴了，但就是停不下来。
That's funny.
真有趣。
So if you have any questions or any other ways to describe feelings, maybe you could
所以如果你有任何问题，或者有其他描述感受的方式，也许你可以
post them on our boards at EnglishPod.com.
把它们发布在我们的论坛上，网址是EnglishPod.com。
There are so many different feelings and most of them have words or names.
有这么多不同的感受，大多数都有对应的词或名称。
Look those up in your dictionaries and let us know.
在字典里查查它们，然后告诉我们。
All right.
好的。
We'll see you guys there.
我们到时候见。
Bye.
再见。
Hey, watch this.
嘿，看这个。